Merrill Moore Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, circa 1920-1957 (Box D1-D219)
  - Boston City Hospital, Boston, Mass. (Box D30)
    - Diets at Boston City Hospital, 1931
    - “E” miscellaneous, 1935-1939 (Box D33)
    - Examination of “bad or nervous” child
    - Eye Outpatient Department
    - “F” miscellaneous, 1935-1941
    - Facilities for functional and personality studies
    - Fan letters, radio
    - Fleming, Robert
    - Fortune magazine
    - Friday clinic
    - Funds and foundations
    - “G” miscellaneous, 1939-1940
    - Gray, Mildred Geneva, 1938-1941
    - Gullstrand ophthalmoscope
    - “H” miscellaneous, 1935-1941 (Box D34)
    - Herpes problem
    - “I” miscellaneous, 1936-1941
    - Illustrations
    - Illustrations for lantern slides
    - International Council on Alcoholism
    - International student
    - “J” miscellaneous, 1935-1942
    - Jetter, Walter W.
    - “K” miscellaneous, 1934-1941 (Box D35)
    - Kielland, Rolf H.
    - Klumpp, Theodore G.
    - Kolb, Lawrence
    - “L” miscellaneous, 1935-1942
    - Latin translators
    - Lennox, William G.
    - Library books wanted
    - Library donations
    - Life magazine
    - Loring, John G.
    - Lowell lectures
    - “M” miscellaneous, 1935-1941
    - “Mc” miscellaneous, 1935-1941 (Box D36)
    - Macmillan Co.
    - Maddock, Stephen
    - Management of the alcoholic probationer
    - Manual
    - Massachusetts Civil League
    - Medical deaths
    - Mental health demonstrations
    - Mental hygiene history
    - Mental status and aphasia exam
    - Mental status examination blank
    - Mental status outline
    - Mental ward
    - Miles Laboratory
    - Miscellany (Box D37)
    - Miscellany (Box D38)
    - Mitchell, Ulysses S.
    - Nerve Outpatient Department (Box D39)
    - Neurological research project
    - New England Journal of Medicine comments
    - New unit course for postgraduate study
    - Notes on history of Boston City Hospital
    - Number of deaths, 1864-1934
    - Number of patients admitted to wards, 1864-1934
    - Number of patients to Nerve Outpatient Department, 1878-1934
    - Number of patients to Neurological Outpatient Department, 1878-1934
    - Number of surgical patients treated at accident room, 1880-1934
    - Number of visits made by all patients
    - Number of weeks treatment given in hospital
    - Nurses
    - “O” miscellaneous, 1937-1941 (Box D40)
    - Old Peacock Sultan Co.
    - Outline of usual day in a patient's life
    - Overholser, Winfred, 1935-1940
    - “P” miscellaneous, 1936-1942
    - Patients accidentally injured and admitted to hospital, 1864-1934
    - Patients born at sea
    - Patients treated in the hospital proper, 1864-1934
    - Pediatrics, form of history
    - Personal, resignation
    - Physical examination
    - Pix Publishing Inc.
    - Possible funds
    - Proofreading symbols
    - Proprietary Association of America
    - Psychiatric examination of a child
    - Psychiatric ward plans
    - Psychiatry at Boston City Hospital
      - Material from annual reports
      - Problem
    - Psychometric tests
    - Putnam, Tracy J., 1938-1940 (Box D41)
    - “Q” miscellaneous, 1937
    - Quarterly Journal of Studies on Alcohol
    - “R” miscellaneous, 1934-1942
    - Raymond, Alice
    - Recommendation letters
    - Reprint list
      - Basic material
      - Reprints sent, 1936-1940
    - Research Council on Problems
      - Of Alcohol
      - General
      - Public health and government
    - Romano, John
    - Rounds, 1937
    - “S” miscellaneous, 1931-1940 (Box D42)
    - Sarcka, Wayne
    - Schizophrenia, remarks on
    - Scientific Committee, Research Council on Problems of Alcohol
    - Scientific Temperance Federation
    - Seydel Chemical Co.
    - Southard Elmer Ernest
    - Spiegel, E.
    - Staff
      - Biographical sketches
      - List
      - Neurological unit
    - Stockman, Harold B.
    - Strauss, Maurice B.
    - Sturgis, Warren
    - “T” miscellaneous, 1935-1940 (Box D43)
    - Temperance Council of the Christian Churches of England and Wales
    - Theses, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Mass.
    - Thomas, Jackson M.
    - Total number of patient days in Boston City Hospital, 1871-1934
    - Trowbridge, Lowell S.
    - “U” miscellaneous, 1935-1940
    - “V” miscellaneous, 1935-1940
    - Veasey, George Ross, 1939
    - Vironamin
    - “W” miscellaneous, 1935-1940
    - Wells, F. L. (Box D44)
    - Wilkie, H. F.
    - Wilson, Mabel R.
    - Women's Christian Temperance Union
    - Works Progress Administration
    - “XYZ” miscellaneous
    - Zottoli, Joseph T
  - Boston Committee for Education on Alcoholism (Box D45)
  - Boston Common People,” 1943-1954
  - Boston Medical Library, Boston, Mass.
    - Book reviews
    - Campaign for funds
    - New England Journal of Medicine
    - Viets, Henry
  - Boston, Mass., newspaper publicity
  - Boston Society of Psychiatry and Neurology, 1952-1957
  - Boston Society of Psychotherapy
  - Boston State Hospital, Boston, Mass.
  - Braceland, Francis J.
  - Bradford, Charles
  - Brady, Joseph T.
  - Brain waves (Box D46)
  - Branscomb, Harvie S.
  - Brattle Theatre Associates
  - Brown, F. Manning, 1936-1942
  - Brown, William J.
  - Bryher, Mrs. W.
  - Burwell, C. Sidney, 1935-1942
  - Bushueff, Boris P.
  - Butler, Jonathan
  - “C” miscellaneous
    - 1936-1957
    - 1936-1957 (Box D47)
  - Caedmon Publishers (Box D48)
  - California Quarterly
  - Cambridge, Mass., lecture
  - Care packages
  - Carpenter, Julia
  - Case Record From a Sonnetorium
    - General correspondence
    - Cartoons
    - Copies for review
    - Mailing list
    - Publicity promotion
  - Centennial Commission, Boston Public Library, Boston, Mass. (Box D49)
  - Central Scientific Co., 1951
  - Cestre, Corles
  - Chenet, Paul C.
  - Chicago Review
  - China
    - Book on
    - Pictures
    - 1946
  - Chinese-Japanese Library, Harvard College, Cambridge, Mass.
  - Chinese lessons
  - Chinese signature
  - Chinese wine
  - Chirkoff, Vladimir A.
  - Chlorpromazine
  - Christian Science Monitor
  - Ciardi, John (Box D50)
    - General
    - Poems sent to
  - Civil defense
  - Claytor, Gertrude R.
  - Clinical Sonnets
    - Correspondence
    - Correspondence with editors of medical magazines
    - Mailing list
    - Miscellany
    - Misprint
    - Proof
  - Cobb, Stanley, 1935-1957 (Box D51)
  - Cole, Anna Russell
  - Cole, John Reece
  - Coleman, Elliot
  - Colleges and universities
  - Colony, Horatio
  - Committee for the Preservation of Medical Standards in Psychiatry
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts
  - Compound MA-110
  - Compton, Walter
  - Conchology (Box D52)
    - Butler Argus
    - “Conchology–A Hobby for Anyone”
    - Hygeia
    - Imago
    - “An Introduction to Conchology”
    - “A Memorandum for Anyone Seeking a Hobby”
    - “A Memorandum to Conchologists”
    - “A Psychiatrist's Note on Shells”
    - “The Reason for Conchology”
    - Resources
    - “Shell Collecting as Occupational Therapy for Psychiatric Patients”
    - Shell lectures and arrangements (Box D53)
    - Shell paper
    - Shells
    - Shells (Box D54)
    - Shells, correspondence
    - “Shells Are Interesting”
    - “Some Notes and Observations on a Sea Shell: Venus Marcenaria”
    - “The Voice of Shells”
  - Conlin, John F. (Box D55)
  - Contacts
  - Contemporary Poetry
  - Copyrights
  - Corman, Cid
  - Crasco, James J.
  - Creative art
  - Creative writing and criticism
  - Crosland, T. W. H.
  - Cross, Leslie
  - Cummins, Samuel
  - Current Medical Digest
    - Article by Moore
    - Article re Moore
  - Cuttle, Tracy D.
  - “D” miscellaneous, 1936-1957 (Box D56)
  - “The Dance of Death” (Box D57)
    - Miscellany
    - Thomas, Charles C.
  - Dartmouth College, Hanover, N.H., 1956-1957
  - Davidson, Donald
  - Davidson, Henry A.
  - Davis, Louise
  - Davis, Thomas and Lydia
  - Davis, Watson
  - “Deaths from Poisoning”
  - Decker, Clarence R.
  - DeCosta, Estelle, 1936-1942, 1953 (Box D58)
  - Deutsch, Albert
  - Dexamyl
  - Dick, Anne
  - “The Dickens Pattern”
  - Diederich, Bernard
  - Distribution lists, 1954
  - “Do You Smoke in Bed?”
  - A Doctor's Book of Hours
  - Dodge, Norman
  - Dolmen Press
  - Dermison–Schering Corp.
  - Downes, Milded G., 1945-1955
  - Dozier, Paul
  - Drewry, Mr. and Mrs. Carleton
  - Drugs, general correspondence (Box D59)
    - 1930-1939
    - 1940-1941, Feb. (Box D60)
    - 1941, Mar.-1942, Feb. (Box D61)
    - 1942, Mar.-1951, Aug. (Box D62)
    - “Acknowledgment to Bromide Intoxication” (Box D63)
    - Addiction
    - Age- marital status
    - Age-sex
    - Beardsley, Walter
    - Brain window studies
    - Bromide group
    - Bromide notes
    - Bromide report
    - Bromides, use of (Box D64)
    - Corrected report of Dec. 1940 meeting
    - Dayton, Neil
    - DIAS symposium
    - Drugs and drug companies
    - Economic status
    - Emerson Drug Co.
    - Gas
    - Gas notes
    - Killian Research Laboratories, Neew York, N.Y. (Box D65)
    - Lesk, Ben, and Lawrence Kolb
    - Marital status
    - “Material on First Drug Paper”
    - Medical examiners' reports
    - “Mental Disease Associated with the Use of Drugs”
    - Metals
    - Metals, notes
    - “Methods for Investigating the Effect of Drugs on Psychological Function”
    - Miscellaneous reports and other material, chiefly on bromide intoxication (Box D66-D73)
    - Miscellaneous reports and other materia, chiefly on bromide intoxication (Box D74)
  - Dunham, Joseph S.
  - Dyer, Murray A., 1936-1942
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1954-1957
  - Eastern Psychiatric Research Association
  - Eastman, Max
  - Eberhart, Richard
  - Eire Society of Boston, Boston, Mass.
  - Eliot, Abigail A. (Box D75)
  - Elliott, Maud Howe
  - Elliott, W. Lyle
  - Ellison, Paul
  - El Salvador
  - Emerson Drug Co.
    - Holy Ghost Hospital
    - Lowthian, Walter
    - McAdoo, Francis, 1951-1954
    - Miscellany
    - New Jersey court case
  - Employment, 1952-1955
  - Encyclopaedia Brittanica, 1949-1951 (Box D76)
  - Engagements, 1955-1957
  - Ephedra
  - Epilepsy
  - Ex-CBI Roundup
  - Excerpta Medica
  - “F” miscellaneous
    - 1936-1942
    - 1954-1955
    - 1956-1957 (Box D77)
  - Fabricant, Noah D., 1953, 1955-1956
  - Fairburn, Rex D.
  - Fant, Glenn
  - Filene, Edward A.
  - Finland, translator
  - First National Bank of Boston
  - Fitts, Dudley, 1936-1956
  - Fitts, Dudley (Box D78)
    - Article on Moore
    - Sonnets
  - Fitzgerald, Edmund B.
  - Flaccus, Kimball
  - Florida medical license
  - Flowers, Paul
  - Forbes, F. Murray, 1951, 1953
  - Forestor, Jack Ballington
  - Forrestal, James
  - Friends in Florida
  - Frost, Robert, 1936-1942, 1952-1953
  - The Fugitive (magazine) (Box D79)
  - Fugitive Poems
  - Fugitive Sonnets
  - Fugitives (group)
  - Fukua, Komei, 1951-1957
  - Fulda, Ludwig
  - Funkenstein test
  - “G” miscellaneous
    - 1934-1939
    - 1936-1942 (Box D80)
    - 1954-1957
  - Games and occupations
  - Garland, Joseph
  - Garland School (Box D81)
  - Gay, R. M.
  - Gayle, R. Findley
  - General Advisory Committee meeting on alcoholism
  - General Heat and Appliance Co.
  - German, Horace
  - German poems
  - German radio
  - German translation
  - “The Ghost Flower”
  - Glattly, H. W.
  - Gleason, Joseph
  - Glenn, C. Leslie
  - Glueck, Bernard, 1936-1942
  - Godown at Sqantum
  - The Golden Bough
  - Goldstein, Murray
  - Goodspeed's Bookstore
  - Gordon, Caroline
  - Gorey, Mr. and Mrs. Edward L.
  - Gorey, Edward St. John
    - Correspondence (Box D82)
    - Illustrations
    - Memoranda
    - Notes
  - Gray, Mildred Geneva, 1936-1942, 1950-1953
  - Gray Pharmaceutical Co.
  - Greenman, Milton Jay
  - Grenfell, Lord
  - Griffin, William J.
  - Group psychotherapy
  - Guggenheim application
  - Guiles, Austin P.
  - “H” miscellaneous (Box D83)
    - 1936-1954
    - 1955-1957 (Box D84)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann
  - Hall, Minna B., 1936-1942
  - Halsey, Margaret (Box D85)
  - Hammacher Schlemmer
  - Hand and Flower Press Manuscripts
  - Harbor pollution
  - Harcourt, Brace and Co.
  - Harrison, Henry
  - Hartford Retreat
    - Abstracts
    - Abstracts, (1 folder) (Box D86)
  - Harvard Advocate
  - Harvard Club of Boston
  - Harvard College, Cambridge, Mass.
  - Harvard College Library, Cambridge, Mass.
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass, lectures
  - Harvard Medical School, Boston, Mass. (Box D87)
    - Appointments
    - Teaching
  - Harvard Psychiatric Clinic
  - Harvard University Gazette
  - Haskin, Frederic J.
  - Hastings, Baird
  - Hayakawa, S. I.
  - Hazelwood, E. Clayton
  - “The Health of Combat Fliers”
  - Heine, Heinrich
  - Hendrick, Ives
  - Henry, Robert S.
  - Herman, Sue, 1936-1942
  - Herring, Robert (Box D88)
  - Hessels, Hattie A.
  - Hightower, Scott
  - Hillman, John W.
  - Hillyer, Robert
  - Hinde & Dauch Paper Co.
  - Hirsch, Nathaniel
  - Hobbies
  - Holley, Fred
  - Holmes, John, poems sent to, 1936-1942, 1952
  - Holzer (U.), Inc.
  - Homan, William P., Jr.
  - Home Indemnity Co.
  - Homes for developmentally disabled children, convalescents, and alcoholics
  - Honig, Edwin
  - Hooper, Bett
  - Hopkins Review
  - Hospitals, miscellany
  - Hound & Horn
  - House
  - House of Chan
  - House plans (Box D89)
  - Housman, A. E.
  - Housman, Robert Fletcher
  - Howe, Henry F.
  - “Herman Hair and Psyche”
  - Huntington, Catherine
  - Huntley Tree Service
  - Hutchinson's Book Store
  - Hypnotism
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1934-1957
  - “I Salute You”
  - Idea for a play
  - Idea for printing poems
  - Ideas for reprinting sonnets
  - Ideas for sonnets
  - Illegitimate Sonnets
  - Illegitimate Sonnets (Box D90)
  - Impastato, David J.
  - Income tax
  - Information (Box D91)
    - Camps
    - Magazine subscriptions
    - Travel
  - Ingersoll, Ralph M.
  - Inspirational poetry
  - Institute of Contemporary Arts
  - Interlingua translations
  - International College of Surgeons
  - Ionnitiu science index
  - Ipsen, Johannes
  - Isaacs, Lewis
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1936-1942, 1954-1957
  - Jacobius, Arnold J.
  - Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md.
  - Johnson, Stanley
  - Jokes
  - Jones, Howard M.
  - Jones, Mrs. Theodore
  - Jones, Theodore F.
  - Josephy, Robert
  - Journal of Clinical and Experimental Psychopathology
  - Journal of Nervous and Mental Diseases
  - Junior League
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1933-1939, 1954-1957 (Box D92)
  - Kahn, Gwyneth
  - Kates, George N.
  - Keener, Gladys M.
  - Keller, Mark J.
  - Kendrick, Katie Lane
  - Kent, Rockwell
  - Kenyon Review
  - Kirby, Helen
  - Kirgo, George
  - Kleeberg, Fred M., 1951-1956
  - Klimenko, George, 1949-1952
  - Knickerbocker, W. S.
  - Koenig, Eleanor O'Rourke
  - Korn, Nancy
  - Koskoff, Reuben (Box D93)
  - Krebs, M. Marguerite
  - Krenensky, Raymond
  - Kreymborg, Alfred
  - Krick, Katherine C.
  - Krock, Arthur
  - Kubie, Lawrence S.
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1936-1942, 1954-1957
  - Labeling paper (Box D94)
  - Lacy, John
  - Lalley, Joseph M.
  - Lamartine
  - Lamont, Tina
  - Landau, David, 1951-1956
  - Landis, William B.
  - Landscape
  - Langner, Lawrence, 1951-1954
  - Laughlin, James, IV
  - Lawrence, Frieda
  - Lear, Edward
  - “Leaves from a Psychiatrist's Notebook”
  - Lectures, 1935, 1937-1939, 1941
  - Lee, Muna (Box D95)
  - Lehrer, Tome
  - Leica Photography
  - Leigh, W. Colston
  - Letters to editors
  - Levin, Benjamin
  - Levine, Maurice
  - Levine, Max
  - Lewis, Wells
  - Library of Congress, 1953, 1956
    - Project
    - Speaking engagement
  - Life and Letters Today
  - Life magazine
  - Liggett, Charles Carson
  - Lindsay, Robert Ople
  - Lingenfelter, Lynwood S., 1952-1953
  - Lists
  - Literary contracts
  - Literary correspondence (Box D96)
    - Great Britain
  - Literary memoranda
  - Literary notes
  - Literary scrapbook
  - Literary works
  - Literature
  - Literature and psychology
  - Lobotomy, legal responsibility
  - Logan Foundation (Box D97)
    - General
    - Financial reports
    - Imago projects
    - Various projects
  - Logan, Mr. and Mrs. Joshua
  - Login (B.) & Son, Inc.
  - Loring, John
  - Loring, Oliver
  - Lovering, E.
  - Lowell, Charlotte, 1936-1942, 1951-1956
  - Lowell, Robert
  - Lucretius
  - Luncheon list
  - Lundborg, Bradford
  - Lundy, John S.
  - Lustig, Mrs. Alfred Lorand
  - “M” miscellaneous (Box D98)
    - 1936-1942
    - 1954-1955, 1957 (Box D99)
    - 1957 (Box D100)
  - “Mc” miscellaneous, 1936-1942, 1954-1955, 1957
  - Maccalman, Douglas
  - McClure, Gen. And Mrs. Robert B., 1951-1957
  - McCord, David
  - McCrohon, Max (Box D101)
  - McDonough, Mary Lou
  - McDougall, William
  - McGill, Ralph
  - MacGregor, Robert M.
  - Mackinnon, George Collier
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - MacLeod, Norman
  - McManus, Dorothy
  - Macmillan Co.
  - McNeil, Mr. and Mrs. Wilfred J.
  - Macpherson, Bryher, 1936-1942
  - Macpherson, Mrs. W.
  - Mailing lists
  - Maine Ballads
  - Malone, Ted
  - Manheim, Leonard F.
  - “Man's Course through Life”
  - Marine Hospital
  - Markson, Robert T.
  - Marquis (A. N.) Co.
  - Marshall project
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Masss.
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass.
  - Massachusetts Medical Society
  - Massachusetts Memorial Hospital, Boston, Mass.
  - Massachusetts Psychiatric Society
  - Mathews, William H.
  - Mayling Soong Foundation
  - Meacham, Harry M.
  - Mears, J. Gerald
  - Medical diagnosis
  - Medical economics
  - Medical libraries
  - Medical papers (Box D102)
    - Index
      - Nos. 11-4
      - Nos. 5-10 (Box D103)
      - Nos. 10-16 (Box D104)
      - Nos. 17-27 (Box D105)
      - Nos. 28-34 (Box D106)
      - Nos. 34-39 (Box D107)
      - Nos. 40-41, 43 (Box D108)
      - Nos. 44, 46-47, 48-54 (Box D109)
      - Nos. 56-60 (Box D110)
      - Nos. 61-68, 71 (Box D111)
      - No. 68 (Box D112-D113)
      - Nos. 69-70, 72-74, 76-77 (Box D114)
      - Nos. 78-81, 83-84 (Box D115)
      - Nos. 85, 87-90, 92-97 (Box D116)
      - Nos. 98-99, 101, 104, 108, 115 (Box D117)
      - Nos. 115-119 (Box D118)
      - Nos. 119-120, 122-123, 125-128, 129 (Box D119)
      - Nos. 131-134, 136, 139 (Box D120)
    - “Advances in Psychotherapy”
    - Alcohol and narcotics
    - Alcohol paper for American Mercury
    - Alcoholism
    - Alcoholism, Equitable Life Assurance Society
    - “Alcoholism: A Disease and a Community Problem”
    - “Alcoholism: A Medical Problem”
    - “Alcoholism and Drug Addiction in the Military Service”
    - “Alcoholism and the Alcoholic”
    - Alcoholism, paper on
    - American Medical Association, clippings
    - American Psychiatric Association
      - Lesk, Benjamin
      - Scientific exhibit
      - Scientific exhibit (Box D121)
    - Atwell paper
    - Book reviews
    - Boston City Hospital, Boston, Mass.
    - Boston Medical Library, Boston, Mass.
    - Bulletins
    - Burlingame's report
    - “Can Mental Hygiene Prevent Neurosis?”
    - Cancer
    - Carpenter, Julia
    - “The Chief Complaints of Neuropsychiatric Patients,” with outline for further investigation
    - Child psychology
    - China
    - Classification of drug intoxication cases at Boston City Hospital, Boston Mass. (Box D122)
    - Community resources as adjuvants to psychotherapy
    - Comparative effect of different drinks
    - “The Complaints of Psychoneurotic Soldiers”
    - Conchology
    - Conditioned reflexes
    - Copyright material
    - Cotton plant
    - Deaths in mental hospitals
    - Diets
    - “The Differential Diagnosis of the Causes of Coma”
    - Differential diagnosis of neuroses and psychoses
    - Dorchester, Daniel
    - Drug addiction
    - “Drug Intoxication and Mental Disease in Massachusetts”
    - Drugs
    - Drugs and psychosis (Box D123)
    - “The Effect of Sodium Bromide Medication upon Psychological Behavior”
    - Electroencephalograph
    - Epilepsy
      - Anatomical records
      - Anatomical statistical data
      - Autopsy material
      - Boston Psychopathic Hospital, Boston, Mass.
      - Broadcast
      - Case studies
      - Correspondence
      - Cost of institutional care
      - Heart and aorta in epileptics
      - Lennox, I.
      - Motor vehicles
      - Psychometrics
      - Solomon, Philip
      - Stanford-Binet tests (Box D124)
      - Statistical data
    - “Eternal Vigilance”
    - “Ethics and Psychotherapy”
    - Gardner, Mrs. Jack
    - Gwaltney, F. W.
    - Heine, Heinrich
    - Helms, Samuel T.
    - “The Incidence and Significance of Alcohol in the History of Criminals”
    - Individual psychology
    - “A Judicial View of the Alcohol Problem”
    - “The Junior Officer and the Alcoholic”
    - Knapp, Philip Coombs
    - Lear, Edward
    - Leonicenus, Nicolas (Box D125)
    - Lesk, Benjamin
    - Liquor: The Servant of Man, correspondence
    - “The Man Who Drinks Too Much”
    - Material for a paper on
      - Daily habits as conditioning
      - Superstition
    - Maulsby, William S.
    - Medical and surgical relief
    - Medical library
    - Memorandum to Moore
    - Mental patients
    - Metropolitan State Hospital, Waltham, Mass.
    - Meyer, Adolf
    - Miscellany (Box D126)
    - Miscellany (Box D127)
    - Museum paper (Box D128)
    - Nervous fatigue
    - Neurology
      - Case studies
      - Harvard
      - Heine's illness
      - Miscellany
      - Private practice
      - Social work
      - Statistics
      - Vitamins and head injuries
    - Neurosyphilis
      - Autopsies
      - Cerebrospinal fluid
      - Cord syphilis
      - General paresis (Box D129)
      - General paretics
      - History
        - Astruc, John
        - Boyle, Antoine Laurent Jesse
        - Gennerich, William
        - Patin, Guy
        - “Story of a Paretic”
      - Immunology in late syphilis (Box D130)
      - Miscellany
      - “A Note on the Epidemiology of Syphilis”
      - Paper on neruosyphilis
      - Personal examination record sheets
      - Problems in clinical neurosyphilis
      - Putnam, Tracy
      - Spinal cord
      - Statistical study
      - “Syphilis and Public Opinion”
    - Neurotics
    - Palindrome project
    - Personal psychology
    - Poisoning
    - Potter, L. G.
    - “The Private Practice of Psychiatry”
    - “The Private Practice of Psychiatry in Greater Boston” (Box D131)
    - “The Psychiatric Point of View”
    - Psychiatry
    - “Psychiatry in Modern Life”
    - “Psychotherapy”
    - Psychotherapy, diagrams for
    - Psychotherapy, symposium on
    - Putnam, Tracy J.
    - Radio address
      - “The Inner World of the Child”
      - “Shell Collecting as Occupational Therapy”
    - Resources, paper on
    - Richmond paper
    - Rush, Benjamin
    - Saunders article
    - Schoedler, Lillian
    - “Sex and Adolescence” (Box D132)
    - Sexual development
    - Shells
    - Singer, H. Douglas
    - Smith, Kline & French Laboratories, article on Dexamyl for
    - Snagrod, Edna, case of
    - Springfield Academy of Medicine, Springfield, Mass.
    - Substandard family
    - Suicide
    - Symposium on alcoholism
    - Syphilis
    - Syphilis (Box D133)
      - Alcoholism
      - Boston City Hospital, Boston, Mass.
    - “The Treatment of a Poet”
    - Visitation plan
    - Webber, Samuel Gilbert
    - “What Can Psychiatry Do to Prevent Neurosis?”
    - “What Happens to Alcoholics?”
    - Whitman, Malcolm D., Jr.
    - Work in progress
  - Medical Protective Co. (Box D134)
  - Menninger Foundation
  - Mercer, Pauline
  - Merrill, Pearl
  - Mezikofsky, Edith
  - Michaels, Joseph J.
  - Miles Laboratories
    - 1952-1957
    - Alexander, Leo
    - Beardsley, Walter, 1950-1952
    - Cawley, John A., 1950-1952
    - Check stubs, 1950-1951
    - Compton, Walter A., 1951-1952
    - Conklin, Raymond L., 1951-1952
    - Crandall, Lathan A., 1952-1954
    - Lerner, W. R., 1950-1951
    - Papers on various subjects
    - Rohr, Joseph H.
    - Sedative drugs reviewed
  - Military career (Box D135)
    - Aabel, Bernard
    - Armstrong, George E.
    - Armstrong, Harry G.